Khaleel AL-Haboub

Software Engineering Innovation Creative Design Entrepreneurship

Passionate engineer with an entrepreneurial spirit who utilizes creativity, leadership, and teamwork to execute solutions that create customer value.

PROFILE

NAME:

Khaleel Abdulrahman Al-Haboub

MOBILE:

(966) 59 422 3341

EMAIL:

Kh.haboub@gmail.com

ADDRESS:

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

NATIONALITY, STATUS:

Saudi Citizen, Single

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/khaleelalhaboub

SKILLS

Through my professional experience, I have acquired various skills and disciplines in **business**, **tech**, and **design**. This results in me communicating the design thinking process and building human-centered products.

BUSINESS SKILLS

Participated in developing business plans and their strategies from a business and technical perspective. Engaged in developing new business ideas including identifying the project's minimum viable product (MVP), and measure /analyzing the users' behavior and their interaction with the product.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Participated in building tech-based projects. Starting with a **project discovery**, **analyzing complex technical requirements**, connecting **design thinking** to **agile sprints**, **designing high-level software architecture**, resulting in **delivering a world-class product** that meets the client expectation.

DESIGN SKILLS

Dealt with various clients and stakeholders shaping products experiences. Starting with understanding the user's persona, mapping user's journey, crafting user's storyboarding, sketching product's wireframes, and prototyping to validate the outcomes with the end-users. This process is being done using various methods including Design Sprint framework.

Also, participated in **the product design process** to produce artifacts that align with business vision and strategy. This process starts with identifying the goals, results in a comprehensive **design system** that provides consistent, reusable **UI (user interface) components** using various tools including **Sketch**, **Adobe XD**, **Photoshop**, **Illustrator**.

EDUCATION

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

B.S., Software Engineering 2009- 2017

Honor Student: 2011, 2013, 2014 Accredited university by **ABET**

RANKED WORLD TOP 189TH BY OS TIMES

TECHNOLOGY & LANG

WEB

- Javascript: Vanilla, NodeJS, AngularJS [1, 2+]
- CSS / Less & Sass
- NPM Gulp Bower
- PHP (Vanilla, Frameworks)
- .Net EF/Core
- Rest APIs GraphQL

MOBILE

- · Android (RxJava, RxAndroid)
- Cross-Platform Apps (ionic)

DESIGN

- Sketch App
- Figma
- Adobe Suite: XD Photoshop illustrator
- Invision App Zeplin Maze

GENERAL

- Java EE
- C/C++, C#
- Oracle Business Process (BPM).
- Cloud Services: Azure, docker
- CMS: WordPress, Drupal
- E-Commerce / M-Commerce: Open Cart, Magento

EXPERIENCE

Indielabs, LLC. / innovation lab Associate

June 2014 – Current

- Designed and led multiple ideation workshops and post-ideation/cross-functional workshops translating stakeholders vision, consumers insights, trends, and competitive landscape into innovative product ideas.
- Developed and managed product innovation activities
- · Coordinated remote development teams and the in-house team.
- Accumulate market know-how, to enhance and manage knowledge on projects.
- Passion for learning, exploring and encourage the development team to utilize and embrace emerging tech, tools, and best practices.

Google / GSA Intern

Jun 2013 - Jun 2014

Google Ambassador Program is an opportunity for students to act as liaisons between Google and their universities.

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:

Worked with local Google teams. Planned and hosted events on campus. Acted as a campus contact for Google teams. Built relationships on campus with faculty and student groups on behalf of Google.

Saudi Aramco / Summer Intern

Jun 2013 – Aug 2013

Worked at Saudi Aramco Entrepreneurship Center (Wa'ed) as a Summer Intern. Wa'ed was pursuing a **pioneering program** to enable KFUPM students to spend their summer training/co-op period **building their own actual companies** around their **own creative business ideas**.

KEY ACTIVITIES:

- Developed business plan for new tech-based ventures.
- Exposed to various methods and concepts for tech-based ventures creation including SaaS, MVP, Bootstrapping, Lean Startup, Business Canvas.
- Exposed to numerous new product design tactics including picking the right venture name, color theory, golden ratio and more.
- Built a new SaaS-based online venture.
- Managed the user experience test sessions, and analyzed the outcomes.

KFUPM / Web Developer (Part-time)

Jan 2011 – May 2013

Designed and developed responsive web applications using SharePoint, PHP, and Bootstrap for the system engineering department at KFUPM.

- · Maintained existing sites based on MS. SharePoint.
- Designed and developed new web services utilizing custom PHP frameworks.
- Adapted and thrived in a work environment with rapidly changing goals.

Freelancing / Web Designer & Developer

2008 - 2012

Worked as a **web designer/ developer** online with various clients. Acquired an essential experience in dealing with a **different type of customers**, working **under pressure** and tight **deadlines**, driving projects **forward**, and mainly the **ability** to **work with minimum supervision**.